我们一直在做的事情之一
One of the things that we've been doing while we've
一直在写代码
been writing the code in this reading
我们一直在记录我们的假设。
is we've been documenting our assumptions.
其中一些文档是Java所必需的，
Some of these documentations are required by Java,
所以写下变量的类型，比如int n，
so writing the type of a variable down, like int n,
意味着n总是指一个整数——实际上
means that n will always refer to an integer-- you're actually
在程序中明确声明--
stating that explicitly in the program--
不能引用字符串、列表或任何其他类型。
and can never refer to a string or a list or any other type.
Java实际上需要这种形式的文档，
And Java actually requires this form of documentation,
它在编译时检查并保证
and it checks it at compile time and guarantees
在你的程序中没有位置
that there's no place in your program
你违反了这个假设。
where you violated this assumption.
也可以声明变量final，
You can also declare variables final,
这是另一种文件。
and that's another kind of documentation.
基本上是说如果你
It's basically claiming that if you
假设这个列表是最后一个变量，那么那个列表
say that this list is the final variable, then that list
变量总是指向同一个列表
variable is always going to point to the same list
对象的初始分配之后。
object after it's initially assigned.
Java也会检查这一点——同样是静态的。
And Java checks that, too-- again, statically.
不幸的是，有很多假设，
There are a lot of assumptions, unfortunately,
Java不会自动检查我们。
that Java doesn't check for us automatically.
这是我们写下的一个例子
Here was with an example of one that we wrote down
在冰雹序列方法的评述中。
in the comment about the hailstone sequence method.
为什么我们需要写下我们的假设？
Why do we need to write down our assumptions?
因为编程充满了它们。
Because programming is full of them.
如果我们不把它们写下来，我们就不会记住它们。
If we don't write them down, we aren't going to remember them.
其他需要阅读或更改我们节目的人
Other people who need to read or change our programs
以后就不认识他们了。
later won't know them.
他们得猜猜我们脑子里想的是什么。
They'll have to guess what was in our head.
这就是导致不一致和错误的原因。
And that's what leads to inconsistency and bugs.
所以这里的一个重要信息是
So one of the big messages here is
你必须写你的程序
that you have to write your programs
有两个目标——不仅仅是交流
with two goals in mind-- not just communicating
使用计算机，不仅仅是说服Java
with the computer, not just persuading Java
你遵守了它的规则
that you're following its rules and that your program is
句法正确，语义正确，
syntactically correct and semantically correct,
同时也和其他人交流。
but also communicating with other people.
你必须使你的程序易于理解，以便
You have to make your program easy to understand so that when
总得有人来修理、改进或适应它
somebody has to fix it or improve it or adapt it
在未来，他们可以做到这一点而不引入bug。
in the future, they can do so without introducing bugs.